Chapter 24
It was now the eighth day since I'd had my accident in the desert,
and I'd listen to the story of the merchant as I was drinking the last drop
of my water supply
I said to the little prince, "these memories of yours are very charming;
but I have not yet succeeded in repairing my plane; I have nothing more to drink;
and I, too, should be very happy if I could walk at my leisure toward a spring
of fresh water!"
"My friend the fox--" the little prince said to me.
"My dear little man, this is no longer a matter that has anything to do with the fox!"
"Why not?"
"Because I'm about to die of thirst..."
He did not follow my reasoning, and he answered me the thing to have a friend,
even if one is about to die.
I, for instance I'm very glad to have a fox as a friend..."
"He has no way of guessing the danger," I said to myself.
"He has never been either very hungry or thirsty.
A little sunshine is all that he needs..."
But he looked at me steadily, and replied to my thought: "I am thirsty, too.
Let us look for a well..."
I made a gesture of weariness.
It is absurd to look for a well, at random, in the immensity of the desert.
But nevertheless we started walking.
When we trudged along for several hours, in silence, the darkness fell,
and the stars began to come out first it made me a little feverish,
and I looked at them as if I were in a dream.
The little prince's last words came reeling back into my memory: "Then you are thirsty, too?"
I demanded.
But he did not reply to my question.
He merely said to me: "Water may also be good for the heart..."
I did not understand this answer, but I said nothing.
I knew very well that it was impossible to cross-examine him.
He was tired.
He sat down.
I sat down beside him.
And, after a little silence, he spoke again:
"The stars are beautiful, because of a flower that cannot be seen."
I replied, "Yes, that is so."
And, without saying anything more, I looked across the ridges of sand that
were stretched out before us in the moonlight.
"The desert looks so beautiful," the little prince added.
And that was true I've always loved the desert.
One sits down on a desert sand dune, sees nothing here's nothing.
Yet through the silence something throbs, and gleams...
"What makes the desert beautiful," said the little prince in his reverie is that
somewhere it hides so well..."
I was astonished by a sudden understanding of that mysterious radiation of the sands.
When I was a little boy I lived in an old house, and legend told us that a
treasure was buried there.
To be sure, no one had ever known how to find it; perhaps no one had ever even
looked for it complete cast an enchantment over that house.
My home was hiding a secret in the depths of its heart
I said the little prince.
"The house, the stars, the desert-- what gives them their Beauties something that is invisible!"
"I am glad," he said, "that you agree with my fox
was the little prince dropped off to sleep, I took him in my arms and set out
walking once more.
I felt deeply moved, and stirred.
It seemed to me that I was carrying a very fragile treasure.
It seemed to me, even, that there was nothing more fragile on all the Earth.
In the moonlight I looked at his pale forehead, his closed eyes, his locks of
hair that trembled in the wind, and I said to myself:
"What I see here is nothing but a shell.
What is most important is invisible..."
As his lips open slightly with the suspicion of a half smile I said to myself, again:
"What moves me so deeply, about this little prince who is sleeping here,
is his loyalty to a flower-- the image of a rose that shines through
his whole being like the flame of a lamp, even when he is asleep..."
And I felt him to be more fragile still.
I felt the need of protecting him, as if he himself were a flame that might
be extinguished by a little puff of wind...
And, as I walked on so, I found the well, at daybreak